<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidyverse tips</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on tidyverse tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello and welcome!</title>
      <link>/post/hello-and-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hello-and-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Check out the packages! The image below shows the core tidyverse packages, and what part of the data science process each of them fits into.
For a full list of all the packages, check out the code chunk below.
tidyverse::tidyverse_packages() ## [1] &amp;quot;broom&amp;quot; &amp;quot;cli&amp;quot; &amp;quot;crayon&amp;quot; &amp;quot;dplyr&amp;quot; &amp;quot;dbplyr&amp;quot; ## [6] &amp;quot;forcats&amp;quot; &amp;quot;ggplot2&amp;quot; &amp;quot;haven&amp;quot; &amp;quot;hms&amp;quot; &amp;quot;httr&amp;quot; ## [11] &amp;quot;jsonlite&amp;quot; &amp;quot;lubridate&amp;quot; &amp;quot;magrittr&amp;quot; &amp;quot;modelr&amp;quot; &amp;quot;purrr&amp;quot; ## [16] &amp;quot;readr&amp;quot; &amp;quot;readxl\n(&amp;gt;=&amp;quot; &amp;quot;reprex&amp;quot; &amp;quot;rlang&amp;quot; &amp;quot;rstudioapi&amp;quot; ## [21] &amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot; &amp;quot;stringr&amp;quot; &amp;quot;tibble&amp;quot; &amp;quot;tidyr&amp;quot; &amp;quot;xml2&amp;quot; ## [26] &amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot; Want to see something else cool?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this site</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>What is the tidyverse? The tidyverse is a collection of open source R packages introduced by Hadley Wickham and the RStudio team that &amp;ldquo;share an underlying design philosophy, grammar, and data structures.&amp;rdquo; That philosophy is outlined in the tidy data paper and the tidy tools manifesto.
Installing the tidyverse The packages in the tidyverse can be loaded into R or RStudio by typing the following commands into the console:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showcase</title>
      <link>/showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/showcase/</guid>
      <description>shiny app for checking blood glucose monitors  The error grids clinicians use to check the accuracy of blood glucose monitors are out-of-date. Regulatory agencies don’t use error grids for approving monitors, but these tools could be useful for testing the performance of recommended products. The Diabetes Technology Society partnered with representatives from the Food and Drug Administration, the American Diabetes Association, the Endocrine Society, and the Association for the Advancement of Medical Instrumentation, and representatives from academia, industry, and government developed the surveillance error grid (SEG) as a tool to assess the degree of clinical risk from inaccurate blood glucose monitors (BGM).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>